start with a square of side length one
cut the square into nine smaller
congruent squares and shade eight of
them like this shading a total of 8 9ths
of the square now repeat the process on
the unshaded Square shading 8 9th of
that 1 nth thus shading an additional 8
over 9 squar of the outer square if we
repeat this process indefinitely we
shade 8 over 9 cubed and then 8 over 9
4th and so on at each stage we shade 8
over 9 to the N if we then think of this
as an infinite process or a limiting
process we can then think of the
limiting diagram which is the entire
shaded square and therefore the infinite
sum that we're interested in which is
the Shaded area is equal to the Shaded
area of the full square or one one
interpretation of this is that 0.8
repeating in base 9 is 1 another
interpretation is that 8 * the infinite
sum of the positive powers of 1 9th is 1
or that the infinite sum of the positive
powers of 1 nth is 1/8